upperdeck.com 2007-12-01

# The Upper Deck Company: Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY STATEMENT**

The upperdeck.com, upperdeckentertainment.com and breakoff.com websites (collectively "the Websites") are hosted by The Upper Deck Company, LLC and Upper Deck Europe B.V. (together "Upper Deck"). At Upper Deck we are committed to protecting your privacy and we comply with the applicable data protection laws. This privacy statement discloses how we collect and use the personal data you provide us. 

**What information is being collected?**

 _Personal information_   
In order to allow you to use the Websites in the best possible way, Upper Deck may request and/or collect personal information (such as name, e-mail address and date of birth) from you on a voluntary basis: 

  * in order to enable you to enter into all pages of the Websites;
  * in order to enable you to register with us;
  * in order to enable you to participate in games, contests, events or promotions;
  * in order to enable you to win prizes;
  * in order to enable you to send questions or comments to Upper Deck;
  * in order to enable you to purchase any goods from Upper Deck (when available);
  * for other services that require registration or subscription.

The requested information is also used by Upper Deck to send you orders, newsletters, information about our company, and promotional material. You personal data is also used to get in touch with you when necessary. When you are ordering products on-line, financial information that is collected is used to bill you for products and services. 

The Websites may contain chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or personal websites. Please remember that any information that is disclosed to any of these, is public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

If you are a citizen of any European country and are under the age of 18, you must provide your parent or legal guardian's email address in order to be eligible and gain full access to the services provided at the Websites. 

If you are a citizen of the United States and are under the age of 13, in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, Upper Deck requires that you provide your parent or legal guardian's email address in order to be eligible and gain full access to the services provided at the Websites. 

_Data collected automatically_

_Use of IP Addresses_

Upper Deck collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to its business partners, and to audit the use of the Websites. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user and to gather broad demographic information. Please review each service prior to use and only use those that disclose information you are comfortable with sharing. 

_Use of Cookies_

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to a visitor's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. A cookie may tell us whether you have visited the Websites before and what pages on the Websites you have viewed. The cookies we use do not collect any personal information about you, provide us with any way to contact you, or extract any information from your computer; they are set to expire after thirty minutes of inactivity. Although most web browsers are set to accept cookies automatically, you can usually change your browser to notify you whenever a website attempts to transfer a cookie to your hard drive or to reject cookies automatically. Consult your browser's Help Screen file for more information. You may occasionally receive cookies from our advertisers. Upper Deck does not control these cookies and they are not subject to this privacy policy. Please consult our advertisers' own privacy policies to learn how they collect and use information. 

**Links to Other Sites**   
Many websites link to Upper Deck and we may link to other websites which we think may be of interest to our visitors. Upper Deck is not responsible for the content of these sites and is not able to control the information that is contained or collected on them. 

Children should always check with a parent or legal guardian before linking to any new sites. Please refer to the privacy policies on these sites to learn how they collect and use information. 

**Opt-out**   
If you would prefer not to receive direct communications with regard to our products and/or services anymore, you may opt-out by following the directions on the bottom of our e-mails to you. 

**Review and Correction of Your Information**   
If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information about you that is maintained by Upper Deck is incorrect and needs to be changed or deleted, please contact us by e-mail and we will be happy to update or remove your personal information accordingly. We may continue to retain your information in our files due to technical and legal requirements, constraints related to the security, integrity and operation of the Websites or to resolve disputes. 

**Disclosure to third parties**   
The personal information collected by us may be shared with Upper Deck Company, LLC (based in Carlsbad, California, USA) and its affiliated companies. These companies will hold and transmit all personal data in the same safe, confidential and secure environment as set out below. Upper Deck may share aggregate data with its partners and advertisers. This data does not contain any personally identifiable information. Upper Deck will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties without your explicit consent. 

**Security**   
We have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while Upper Deck strives to protect your personal information, Upper Deck cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. 

**Policy for children under 18 years of age**   
If you are a citizen of a European Country and under the age of 18, or a citizen of the United States or Canada and under the age of 13 you must provide your parent or legal guardian's email address in order to be eligible and gain full access to the services provided at the Websites. In addition, we will provide your parents with the ability to: (a) review the personal information we have collected from you; (b) refuse to allow any further collection or use of your personal data; and (c) remove your records from our database. Upper Deck does not require children to provide any more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in any of our site activities. 

In the event that Upper Deck learns that you are under the age of 18 in Europe or 13 in the United States or Canada, Upper Deck will contact your parent or legal guardian (collectively, "Parents") to seek consent before we further process your personal data. 

Until consent is provided, we will neither collect any additional information about you nor use the information we've collected except for the purpose of seeking consent. If we do not have your parent's consent within 30 days we will destroy all personal data we have received from you and you will have only limited access to the Websites. 

Once consent is provided, you will receive an e-mail message confirming that you will have full access to the Websites. This e-mail should be received within a week of receiving your Parent's consent. 

Even after a parent has given consent for Upper Deck to collect personal information from his/her child, the parent may at any time contact Upper Deck's Privacy Policy Administrator to review, alter or delete information that was previously collected. A parent may revoke consent by completing [this form](http://www.upperdeck.com/member/parentrevoke.aspx) and either mailing or faxing it to Upper Deck's Privacy Policy Administrator at the address or number listed below. 

**Questions and complaints**   
Any questions or complaints about Upper Deck or this privacy statement can be addressed by contacting us at upperdeck.com. 

Upper Deck (Europe BV)   
Flevolaan 15   
1382 JX Weesp   
The Netherlands   
Fax number: (011) 31 294 461 601 

The Upper Deck Company, LLC   
5909 Sea Otter Place   
Carlsbad, California 92010   
Fax number: (760) 929-3194
